ERVINS ZAGARS

FRONT-END WEB <u>DEVELOPER</u>

Email: ervins.zagars@gmail.com
Portfolio: https://ervinszagars.com/
LinkedIn: https://github.com/ErvinsZ/

A coder who is currently specializing in front-end development. Has also understanding of backend operations through building full MERN stack applications in a team setting.

Before worked in sales as a sales agent and later on as a team lead in the same company

HARD SKILLS:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB, Git, Github, SCRUM

SOFT SKILLS:

Team work, Task prioritization, Constructive feedback

EXPERIENCE

Revpanda Digital Agency 2020-currently

Web Developer

- Building front-end based on designs provided with Adobe XD and Figma by using HTML and CSS
- Creating front-end functionality by using JavaScript and Jquery
- Optimizing FCP, LCP, and CLS scores to make sure website has a good SEO ranking.
- Recent work done for client's:
 - https://casinobee.com/
- https://revpanda.com/
- https://casinojinn.com/

International Travel Network 2017-2020

Sales agent 2018-2019

- Tremendously improved communication skills by performing over the phone sales
- Got promoted to work with business class clients after nine months of being in the company

Sales Team Lead 2019-2020

- Took over an existing team consisting of individuals from many different countries and diverse backgrounds
- Improved interpersonal relationships within the team through team building activities
- Increased profits produced by the team by 40%

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS:

CryptoVisualizer (JS, React)

Code: https://bit.ly/2STZ3vb

- Worked with two third party API's (cryptocompare.com.highcharts.com)
- Dynamically displayed information of user selected crypto currency on a graph.
- Used CSS Grid and styled-components library

Linkedin Clone (MERN Full Stack App)

Code: https://bit.ly/2SWT88v

- Acquired understanding of full-stack development and how front-end, back-end are connected together
- Experience gained working in a team by following SCRUM principles
- Created REST API routes for user profiles using NodeJs

Spotify Mockup (HTML, CSS)

Code: https://bit.ly/3nReDWt

- Created responsive design to fill all screen sizes
- Interface built using Bootstrap library

EDUCATION

Strive School 04.2020 - 10.2020

MERN STACK

- MongoDB, ExpressJs, React, NodeJs
- Got also introduced to relational databases, specifically PostgreSQL

Swansea University 2014-2017

BS Criminology and Criminal Justice

- Cybercrime: Deviance, Crime and Terror
- Terrorism and the Global Response
- Biological, Psychological and Social Crime Theories